Thorvaldur Konradsson

Date of Birth: 25/12/1976. Nationality: Icelandic (**EU/EFTA**). Address: Calle Torres Miranda 14, 28045 Madrid, Spain

Tel: + 34 635 02 65 62

Email: thor@thorvaldur.net / Skype: t_konradsson



OBJECTIVES

I am a driven and highly versatile Learning Systems Manager, Developer, Instructional Designer and Trainer with years of experience at an international level. I have worked on different projects for international companies and organizations with a global presence such as Nestlé, Santander Group, Amaris, Adecco and UNITAR. My ability with languages along with my interpersonal skills and openness to partake in diverse and demanding projects has seen me acquire a vast experience that I hope to build on in the future.

EDUCATION AND ABILITIES

York St. John University. MBA Leading Innovation and Change. 2018 – current.

University of Iceland. Italian and Philosophy, 80% of 120 ECTS complete. 2004-2007.

Certified Professional Scrum Master, May 2018.

ITIL® Foundation v03 Certification, November 2015

I completed the first year of **Computer Science** at the University of Iceland acquiring a basic knowledge of **Software Development** and **HTML**. 2003.

Professional Scrum Master I Certificate in May 2018

ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management in November 2015

Course in 'Advanced Programming of Web Pages in PHP and JavaScript and Databases' with the Instituto Europeo de Estudios Empresariales. 2011. 300 hours. Grade: High.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Vector ITC Group. – January 2019 – current. – Consultant / Developer / LMS management

Work for and with different clients in various aspects involving training and learning, documentation and Learning Management System's management.

Telepizza Group: Management of a Moodle Learning Management System with over 25.000 students which includes User, Course and Itinerary management. Coordination between stakeholders. Overseeing the transfer of all training to an updated version of the Learning Management System on a new server.

Technical and functional administration of a Moodle Learning Management. Content creation in Articulate Storyline and RISE.

Technical documentation of Telepizza Group applications and processes.

Deutsche Bank: Technical and functional management of a Moodle LMS which administers procedural and financial courses to external contractors of the bank. Coordination between stakeholders and technical assistance in the creation of courses, categories and itineraries.

Spanish Ministry of Justice: Technical assistance in implementing an updated Moodle Learning Management System in the Spanish Ministry of Justice.

Technologies in LMS management: Moodle, SQL, PHP, HTML, Web Services

Content Creation technologies: Articulate Storyline 360, HTML, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Documentation technologies: Sphinx, GitHub Pages, HTML

Methodology: ADDIE for Instructional Design, Agile, Scrum Framework

Based in: Madrid, Spain

UNITAR. - October 2019 - December 2019. - e-Learning Specialist

I was contracted to help in the creation of a multimedia e-learning course on "Understanding data and statistics better – for more effective SDG decision making".

Development of e-learning course:

- Create 5 modules in Articulate RISE from subject matter experts' documents.
- Implement quizzes using Articulate Storyline.
- Design graphics and overall look-and-feel.
- Prepare product for publication.
- Work with coordinators in enhancing user experience.
- **Technologies**: Articulate Storyline 360, Photoshop.
- Methodology: ADDIE for Instructional Design
- **Based in**: Madrid, Spain

Link to course: https://learnatunitar.org/course/view.php?id=498

UNITAR. – February 2019 – March 2019. – e-Learning Specialist

I was contracted to help in the creation of a multimedia e-learning course on the "Introduction to the 2030 Agenda" in Spanish.

Development of e-learning course:

- Create 3 modules in Articulate Storyline from translated documents.
- Improve visual aspects.
- Publish product for publication
- Work with coordinators in enhancing user experience.
- **Technologies**: Articulate Storyline 360,
- Methodology: ADDIE for Instructional Design
- **Based in**: Madrid, Spain

Link to course overview:

https://www.unitar.org/courses/mooc-introducci%C3%B3n-la-agenda-2030-una-nueva-agenda-para-unmundo-sostenible-20203rd-ed-6467

AMARIS / NESTLÉ. – July 2017 – October 2018. – e-Learning Specialist / Web developer

The Application Development Services department at Nestlé is responsible for assisting project managers in the development of in-house applications and software.

Through AMARIS I was contracted to create an interactive course on Agile Software Development (ASD) to raise awareness at Nestlé on everything related to Agile in the development of software.

Development of e-learning course:

- Work alongside subject experts to analyze current material.
- Transform training and assessment material, PPT and Word, into interactive e-learning.
- Create posters and an interactive animation to promote ASD.
- Compose questions on ASD to use as interactive quizzes.
- Prepare a course packet as a product ready to be published.
- Preparation of PPT and Articulate Rise presentations to use as promotional material.

Additional responsibilities:

- Assist in promoting ASD during DevOpsDays exposition in-house.
- Preparation of QnA Maker Chatbot for use on intranet and Skype
- Update SharePoint ADS intranet

Technologies: Articulate Storyline 360, Articulate Rise, GIMP, Illustrator, Office, QnA Maker, SharePoint, Azure, CREA, Adobe Premiere Pro

Methodology: ADDIE for Instructional Design, Agile, Scrum Framework.

Based in: Geneva and Vevey, Switzerland

References:

- **Régis Comazzi**: Agile Community Lead. Nestlé GLOBE IS/IT. <u>regis.comazzi@nestle.com</u>.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/r%C3%A9gis-comazzi-4823754/

- Clovis Charpentier: Manager. AMARIS. charpentier.clovis@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/clovischarpentier/

UNITAR / UNOSAT. – August 2016 – November 2016. – e-Learning Specialist

An autonomous UN body established in 1963, the **United Nations Institute for Training and Research** (www.unitar.org) is a training arm of the United Nations System.

UNOSAT is a technology-intensive program delivering imagery analysis and satellite solutions to relief and development organizations within and outside the UN system.

I was brought in as a consultant to UNOSAT to develop a course/tutorial on the use of Geospatial Information Technologies in Disaster Risk Reduction. The course is intended to raise awareness on GIT and DRR among stakeholders in the horn of Africa.

Development of e-learning course:

- Analyze subject experts' documentation and extract relevant information.
- Transform existing PPT training material into interactive e-learning modules.
- Mitigate between technical material and non-technical audience.
- Complete graphical design of the course and player.
- Create simple interactive animations and games.
- Work with coordinators and subject experts on improvements.
- Prepare a course packet as a product ready to be published.

Technologies: Articulate Storyline 2, Adobe Captivate, Camtasia, Photoshop, SCORM, Office

Methodology: ADDIE for Instructional Design

Based in: Geneva, Switzerland

Additional countries involved: Kenya, Thailand

References:

Valeria Drigo: Project Coordinator. UNITAR/UNOSAT. <u>valeriadrigo410@gmail.com</u>.
 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/valeria-drigo-78b59868.

Vector ITC Group. – March 2012 – September 2015. – Consultant/Developer/Trainer

Vector ITC Group is an international software developer. Part of the Santander Group, it specializes in developing solutions for a wide range of international clients.

Since joining Vector in 2012 I have been involved in multiple projects based on very different technologies and methodologies and working with and for such prestige clients as the Santander Group, Mapfre, UNED, McDonald's and Sacyr.

Developing e-learning courses:

- Analyze documentation available and create storyboards for courses.
- Working with subject experts to develop the courses using multiple methodologies.
- Implementing and constructing courses using different tools.
- Quality Control and improvements of courses.
- Creating course manuals and technical documentation.
- Producing video tutorials and simulations of applications.
- Identifying Target Audience and creating follow-up reports.

Technologies: Flash, Storyline, Adobe Captivate, Camtasia, HTML5, iSpring, SCORM, Office, Java, PHP

Environments: Moodle, Standalone Players, Company LMS, Wordpress

Methodology: Santander Learning Methodology, ISBAN Methodology, Various Company Methodologies

Training of Santander Group's IT personnel:

- Homologated trainer of IT professionals in English and Spanish.
- Face-to-Face and videoconference classes in over 10 countries.
- Updating technical documentation used in training.
- Creating manual on use of processes, tools and applications.
- Producing video tutorials and simulations of applications/tools taught.
- Training of additional trainers.

Technologies: Office, Adobe Captivate, iSpring, Camtasia, Wiki, Rochade

Environments: Classroom, Virtual Classroom, Wikipedia

Methodology: Santander Learning Methodology, ISBAN Methodology

Based in: Madrid, Spain; Milton Keynes, UK; and Mönchengladbach, Germany

Virtual classrooms in the following countries: Europe (Poland, Portugal, Germany, UK, France, Italy),

LATAM (Brazil, Mexico, Chile, Argentina, Colombia, Peru, Puerto Rico), USA

Mapping and Technical Documentation of the Santander Group's Banking Applications:

- Finding a solution to develop DITA documents and publishing them as HTML in an Eclipse InfoCenter environment.
- Querying Application information from two different databases to use in documents.
- Automating the process of writing query results into DITA documents ready for publication.

Technologies: DITA, PHP, XML, HTML, Eclipse, Rochade, IBM Host, SQL, Office, Wiki

Environments: Eclipse InfoCenter, Wikipedia

Methodology: Santander Publications Methodology

Creating Social Network/e-learning environment:

- Writing commercial, functional and technical documentation used in the development of a Social Enterprise Network.
- Implemented the use of BigBlueButton as a videoconferencing solution.
- Developed a Social Network/e-learning environment by combining a Mahara and Moodle.
- Creating prototype environment with example courses, documentation and information used to commercialize the Social Network

Technologies: HTML, PHP, TPL, Ubuntu, CentOs, Joomla, Drupal, SQL, XML **Environments**: Moodle LMS, Mahara ePortfolio System, BigBlueButton, Redmine

Methodology: Vector Project Management, LMS implementation, ITIL

Mapping Expertise Gap in UNED's IT Team:

- Evaluating the expertise of the UNED IT Team
- Calculating the loss in IT Team expertise by key member leaving
- Plan Optimal Expertise Distribution for IT Team
- Present a 9-month Training Plan for IT Team and Trainers to follow

Technologies: UNED LMS, AOL, YML, HTML **Methodology**: Four Key Steps to Gap Analysis

Integration of a global employee database for MAPFRE:

- Transferred to client to assist MAPFRE in the implementation of a global database of the group's employees.
- Coordination between Human Resources in Spain and the rest of the 23 countries.
- Assisting the countries with the technical and functional requirements of the database.
- Finding solutions to the varied employee databases and how they could be integrated more easily into the new global database.

Technologies: SAP, SQL, META4 **Based in**: Madrid, Spain

Additional countries involved: Malta, Thailand, UK, USA, Philippines, Puerto Rico

References:

- Aaron Ranson: Director of Consulting and Solutions Services. Vector ITC Group.

<u>aranson@vectorsf.com</u>. Tel.: +34 911 830 659 / +34 605 233 713.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaronranson.

- Gonzalo Poblaciones: Head of Knowledge Management. Vector ITC Group.

gpoblaciones@gmail.com. Tel.: +34 605 252 996.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gonzalopoblaciones.

BuonGiorno! – May 2011 – July 2011. – **Technical Documentation**

BuonGiorno! is an international company specializing in the development of paid apps and mobile solutions.

Hired to write the technical documentation in English for a multimedia application BuonGiorno were developing. The application was intended to provide, music, films, videos, ringtones, etc. to a worldwide audience.

Application written in JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) technology.

Based in: Madrid, Spain

AdeccoXpert. - Adecco Group. March 2008- March 2011. - e-learning Development

AdeccoXpert is an application used globally by Adecco to test the knowledge of its candidates through e-learning and Aptitude Tests. Through AdeccoXpert over 3 million tests are sent out annually to over 2 million aspiring candidates.

Since my incorporation in the AdeccoXpert project in 2008 as a training material developer, I have gradually taken on more responsibilities. As of summer 2010 I was responsible for the developing of Software, Audio and Aptitude Tests, working closely with countries and meeting their requirements.

- Developed Microsoft Office e-learning courses in Dutch, French, German, Greek, Italian, Polish, Portuguese, Russian and Spanish.
- Developed Aptitude Tests in Chinese, Croatian, French, Greek, Italian, Polish, Russian, Serbian, Slovak and Spanish.
- Developed Audio Tests (Listening and Written) in Spanish and Portuguese.
- Assisted the Technical Team in implementing courses.
- Worked closely with the countries in developing their courses.
- Created documents for the countries to review Beta versions of courses.
- Help Desk to countries in resolving issues related to courses.
- Q&A (Functionality and grammar).
- XML programming to adjust courses to each language.

Technologies: HTML, XML, Photoshop, Office, Adecco Translation Tool

Environments: Adecco LMS **Based in**: Madrid, Spain

Additional countries involved: France, India, Nigeria, Russia, Poland, Croatia, Italy, China, Greece

References:

Amy Greenberg: Product Manager. Operational Excellence (Candidate Assessment).
 amy.greenberg@adecco.com / amyngreen@yahoo.com. Tel.: +34 661 210 019.

LANGUAGES

Icelandic: Native.

English: Excellent: spoken, written and read.
Spanish: Excellent: spoken, written and read.
French: Good: spoken, written and read.
Italian: Good: spoken, written and read.